# **Nathaniel Dragusin**

# Software Engineer

#### **About**

As an enthusiastic developer, I enjoy creating scalable products that improve based on metrics and constant feedback. With valuable experience in head-first tackling problems in startups I have worked with in the past, I compose myself as a keen, curious learner.

# **Experience**

OCTOBER 2023 - FEBRUARY 2024

FuturU, UK - Software Engineer

Revamped the entire front-end of an AWS-powered health education app, reducing the codebase by 61% and enhancing user experience with new widgets, components, and animations, including a sustainable architecture supported by documentation.

SEPTEMBER 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2023

#### **Good With, UK** - Lead Software Developer

- Led team in developing a modular fintech app in Flutter using open-banking technology and clean architecture, securing over £600k in grant funding.
- Pioneered the establishment of our tech stack, supporting a web app, mobile app, admin
  panel and cloud applications, overseeing CI/CD and managing Google Cloud infrastructure
  using Node.JS and Terraform.
- Innovated frameworks for seamless content integration and educational platforms, including managing a full-stack chatbot used in machine learning.
- Ensured regulatory compliance and on-time delivery of product features through strategic project planning and product management in a self-organising team.

MARCH 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

# Oniksa, UK - Full-stack Developer

Developed market entry with a user-tested Flutter fintech app, utilising BLoC and RESTful APIs and sticking to strict quality standards through test-driven development.

AUGUST 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2020

#### **VIPAS, Romania** - Software Developer

- Prototyped Flutter app for electric vehicle users, implementing authentication, geolocation, maps, and profile creation.
- Cut operating costs by researching and benchmarking open-source transportation routing software.

# **Personal Projects**

#### LAN Chat - Github, Google Play

This lightweight local network chat app uses TCP/UDP packets, supporting text, image, file sharing, client discovery, and a clean UI.

Published on Google Play with over 5000 instals, built using a handcrafted LAN framework for heartbeat recognition, custom names, and messages in local packets.

#### Contact

nathandevelops.com dragusinnathaniel@gmail.com github.com/nathanielxd +44 7838 005546

## **Skills**

Flutter, C#, TypeScript, Node.JS, .NET, Firebase, Google Cloud, Terraform, Git, CI/CD, TDD.

#### **Awards**

#### **1st Place National Hackathon**

Mobile App Development, iTEC Romania 2019

#### **1st Place National Contest**

Minecraft in Education, Microsoft Youthspark 2019

#### **Education**

#### **DipHE Computer Science**

University of Birmingham 2020-2022

#### **Based In**

Bristol, United Kingdom

#### Lethologica - Google Play

Look up words in the dictionary and save them into this easy-to-use, minimalistic vocabulary.

Lethologica is a Flutter app with a clean design that provides English queries, auto suggestions, and offline word vocabulary.

## MagicHome - Github

C# and .NET library enabling control of MagicHome-compatible light bulbs and LED strips within the same network.

It was developed by reverse engineering and packet listening smart lighting at home.

#### FlutterFall - Github

Architectural design pattern for Flutter with modular directory structure, repository pattern, and 3-layered object separation.

It is bundled with helper tools such as VSCode extensions and snippets for efficient pattern implementation.

#### **Tapline**

Flutter app for brewing enthusiasts with a recipe editor, calculators for bitterness, colour, ABV, OG, and assistant managing timers and to-dos for a seamless brewing experience.